Guide to the Abraham Yates, Jr. papers, 1604-1825 [bulk 1760-1796]
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- CHRONOLOGICAL LIST
  - 172. Bancker, Gerard (Treasurer). Receipt given Abraham Yates Junr. for "Interest facility Certificates" amounting to $72. 405. A. D. S. 1 p. folio, 1786 February 20
  - 173. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed te Abm. G. Lansing, Post Master, Albany. Mentions Duer, Bancker, Osgood & refers to the Oath of Office which he was required to take. A, L. S. 2 p. folio, dated New York, 1786 March 1
  - 174. Osgood, Samuel; Livingston, Walter; Lee, Arthur, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. "It is our Duty to remind you. that until you have taken the Usual Oath of Office we cannot Consider you as a Commissioner of the Loan Office under the, 1786 March 1
  - 175. Visscher, Matthew, to Abraham Yates Esq. Refers to a Petition of George G. Klock's & touches upon many political points. "Does not the Confederation expressly declare that Delegatee shall be annually appointed and take their Seats In Congress on the, 1786 March 6
  - 176. Osgood, Samuel; Livingston, Walter; Lee, Arthur, to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. Transmitting a Resolve of Congress In reference to the Oath of Office & returning the Oath left by Yates at the office of the Board of Treasury. L. S. 2 p. quarto. dated Bo, 1786 March 28
  - 177. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Mr, Hendrick Gardineer, near Upper Ferry. Referring to the approaching election and the "Great Exertions made by the Manor and Schuyler Interest to prevent the Election of our Old Friend Abraham Yates Junr". "They ar, 1786 April 19
  - 178. Smith, William, addressed to Abraham Yates Esqr, in Albany. Refers to him serious illness & sending remembrances to his friends in Albany, A, L. S. 1 p. folio, dated Manr. St, George, 1786 July 18
  - 179. Yates, Abraham, Junr. draft of his letter to William Smith, Long Island. Expressing sympathy on account of his illness & extending an invitation to himself & wife to make a visit in. Albany. 2 p. Quarto, dated Albany, 1786 July 27
  - 180. Lansing, Abraham G. to Abraham Yates Junr, Referring to a Report of the Loan Office & mentioning Col. Barber, Mr. Livingston, Mr. Osgood & others. Also mentions Mr. Bancker's serious injury by a fall from a horse. "The Business of the State will in c, 1785 December 3
  - 181. Milligan, James (Comp, of the Treasury), to "The Honorable The Board of Treasury". Refers to the settlement of Abraham Yates Junr's accounts as Loan Officer. Copy of document, 4 p. large folio, dated Comptroller's Office, 1786 December 9
  - 182. Barber, William, to Abraham Yates Esquire, Bespeaking his assistance in procuring an appointment as a member of the Board of Commissioners. A. L, S. 2 p. quarto, Bated Poughkeepsie, 1787 February 1
  - 183. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. to the cars of Wm. Bedlow Esqr., New York. Relating to Loan Office matters, an altercation; with the Treasury Board &c "Barber's situation is perhaps delicate from the prospect be has of con, 1787 April 8
  - 184. Yates, Robert, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Member of Congress at New York. Refers to the Philadelphia Convention. "Additional Rules have since been entered Into, one of which strictly prohibits the communication of its business until the, 1787 June 1
  - 185. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter in his autograph. Refers to canvassing the votes for Senator. 1 p. folio, dated New York, 1787 June 2
  - 186. Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr, "The Election for representatives in Assembly has gone against us Gansevoort, Ten Eyck, Gordon, Van Ingen, Van Orden, Younglove & Sickles Mrs. Robert Livingston of the Manor Is also Dead". Autograph letter, 1787 June 4
  - 187. Silvester, Peter, addressed to The Honble Abraham Yates Esqr., New York. Concerning the overpayment of a certain Mr, Beache, Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Kinderhook, 1787 June 19
  - 188. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junior Esquire, New York. Refers to his brother John Lansing Jr. and Mr. Hamilton. "We have reports hers that Mr, Paine is employed to write in favor of the British form of Government - and that the sys, 1787 August 26
  - 189. Yates, Peter W., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr., Leonard Gensevoort & John D. P. Ten Eyck, Esquires, Pokespsy. Refers to a petition presented to the Legislature by Mary Elmendorph. Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated New York, 1988 January 21
  - 190. Lott, Abraham, to The Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. of the Senate at Poughkeepsie. Refers to hie confinement in Goal & a Memorial which he wished to have laid before the Legislature. Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated New York, 1788 January 22
  - 191. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Poughkeepsie. "I am of Opinion that the Measures adopted by Massachusetts Bay will give a tone to the determination of this Important Matter in our Legislature. It is roundly asserted here, 1788 January 23
  - 192. Smith, Melancton, addressed to The Honl. Abraham Yates Junr. Esq., Poughkeepsie, "Report here said that you was defenct and that your funeral had been solemnised with great pomp, We have nothing authentic from, the Convention of Massachusetts. The de, 1788 January 23
  - 193. Smith. Melancton, addressed to The Honl. Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Poughkeepsie Refers to the adoption of the Constitution. "He advises that the Sum granted as a donation should be acknowledged as a debt, and Included In the Obligations given to the, 1788 January 28
  - 194. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., to the care of the postmaster, Poughkeepsie. "Politics are still at a stand. A report has been circulated here for some days informing that the Convention of Massachusetts had rejected the, 1788 January 31
  - 195. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing. "Antifederal Business is Carried on in this County with spirit. New York they are all in a panic with the adopt ion. of Massaahusetts", A. L, S. 1 p. folio, Dated Poughkeepsie, 1788 February 28
  - 196. Lansing, Abraham G. a copy of Document addressed to Melancton Smith Esq., signed by Abra G. Lansing, John Lansing Junr., Jeremiah Van Renseelaer & others. Requesting that a printer be sent up from New fork with his press to look after the publication, 1788 March 1
  - 197. Lansing, Abraham G., to Abraham Yates Junr. The body of the letter refers to the desire of Lansing & his friends to have an unprejudiced printer in Albany. A postscript in handwriting of & signed by Henry Oothoudt, A. L, S. 2 p. folio, 1788 March 2
  - 198. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., to the house of Mr. Powers, Poughkeepsie. "Our Measures have hitherto a most favourable aspect and if we Continue our Exertions we have the greatest prospect of success". Autograph letter s, 1788 March 12
  - 199. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G, Lansing, Relating to politics. "They Honour me with being at the head of that party and to that end have bean all the scurrilous publications". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Senate Room, Poughkeepsie, 1788 March 14
  - 200. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G, Lansing. "Wether We will breake up this week and when is made uncertain by Mr. Duane, Lawrence and Vanderbilt arrived here (It is said) for the express purpose of Carrying the Legislature to New York", Autograph l, 1788 March 18
  - 201. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr, in Congress, New York. "The Majority of the Assembly is much greater than we had reason to expect. Communicate the agreeable information to his Excellency and all our Friends". Autograph let, 1788 May 27
  - 202. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abm. G. Lansing Esq., Albany. Reports a conversation held with Col. Hamilton. "I told him rather than to adopt the Constitution I would risk a government of Jew. Turk or Infidel. I told him the government that were, 1788 May 28
  - 203. Visscher, Matthew, addressed to Ab. Yates Junr., John McKesson and Melancton Smith Eaqr., New York. "The Antifederalists had a Majority in every District except the City of Albany". Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, 1788 May 30
  - 204. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. in Congress, New York Refers to the returns of the recent election & the probability of a Majority In the State. "Should any System be proposed with you it will be well to forward a Sketch o, 1788 June 1
  - 205. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Abraham G. Lansing. Refers to the Assembly Election & the hopes of the Federalists for the adoption of the Constitution. A. L S. 1 p. folio, dated New York, 1788 June 1
  - 206. Smith, William, to Abraham Yates Esqr. Refers to the New Constitution. "It Strikes me with Amasement that Good Whigs who Suffered and underwent what they Did Should turn tail too". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Manr. St. George, 1788 June 12
  - 207. Van Rensselaer, Jeremiah, to Abraham Yates Junr. "The Montgomery Delegates are Expected in torn this Evening. Judge Oothoudt, the Mayor and such others as May be Ready Embark this Evening With Capt. Van Woert for Poughkeepsie". Autograph letter signe, 1788 June 13
  - 208. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., New York. "It appears to be the opinion of all those whom I have conversed with that the Constitution will be effectually emended previous to its adoption - or that it will be Totally rejec, 1788 June 15
  - 209. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing Esq., Post Officer, Albany. Refers to the adoption of the Constitution. "The members from this place seem determined not to adopt (without previous amendments) the all the others should. What ste, 1788 June 15
  - 210. Oothoudt, Henry, addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. In Congress, New York. "On the 17th the Convention met - 53 Members present, The Chancellor opened with along Oration - Moved a Resolution that the Proposed plan of Government be Discu, 1788 June 21
  - 211. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. to the care of Willm, Bedlow Esqr., New York. Refers to the Constitutional. Convention. "This Circumstance the Federal gentleman will no doubt avail themselves of and procrastinate the Busin, 1788 June 22
  - 212. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abm. G. Lansing Esq., Post Master, Albany. Refers to his suit against Claxton, the printer, & gives some of his Ideas in regard to the education of children, Autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, 1788 June 23
  - 213. Yates, Abraham, Junr., addressed to Abraham G. Lansing Esqr., Albany. "Whilst I am writing advise is brought that New Hampshire had adopted the New Constitution which bread such an inattention to the Business the Southern Members to write letters to, 1788 June 25
  - 214. Yates, Abraham, Junr., 2 drafts of letter in his autograph to the Governor, Refers to the news from New Hampshire & the Loan from Holland. "L'Hommedieu last Monday mentioned that he had from a strong Federal (Dr. Tillotson) that the Anties went upon, 1788 June 27
  - 215. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to the Hon, Abraham Yates Esq., In Congress, New York, Interesting letter In relation to the adoption of the Constitution. "The Federalists appear much elated by the adoption of the Constitution in N. Hampshire. ' We, 1788 June 27
  - 216. Oothoudt, Henry, addressed to Honorable Abraham Yates Junr. in Congress, New York, "Yesterday we Proceeded to the Consideration of the first Clause of the 8th Section of the first Article". A, L. S. 1 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie, 1788 June 27
  - 217. Clinton, George (Gov.), to the Honble Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. "The Convection are assembling and In a few minutes I must take the Chair. The Antis are firm & I hope and believe will remain so to the End". Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated P, 1788 June 28
  - 218. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr. to the care of William Bedlow Esqr., New York. An interesting letter referring to the Convention. "The Federalists here plume themselves much on the accession of New Hampshire, They can now, 1788 June 29
  - 219. Yates, Abraham, Junr. addressed to Abraham G. Lansing, Post Master. Albany. It appears that the Anties are neither to be frowned or flattered out of their opinion". Also refers to the lean made in Holland & the proposal to make a new loan. Autograph, 1788 June 29
  - 220. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Hon. Abraham Yates Esquire, New York. Interesting letter referring to a heated argument between Mr. Lansing and Mr. Hamilton in the Constitutional Convention, on the necessity of the existence of the State governme, 1788 June 30
  - 221. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esqr., New York. Referring to a quarrel In the city of Albany between the Federalists and the Antis, caused by "our Friends and their Antagonists being heated with Liquor". "I hope If the Constitu, 1788 July 9
  - 222. Lansing, Abraham G. addressed to Abraham Yates Junr, Esq., New York- Referring to the Constitutional Convention. "Mr. Jones it is said is so much Intimidated by the Threats of the Federalists that he does not any more take as active part. M. Smith is, 1788 July 20
  - 223. Lansing, Abraham G., addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, New York. Referring to the plans of the Federalists in Albany for a celebration in honor of the adoption of the Constitution. "The Bill of Rights which is interwoven with the adoption is, 1783 August 3
  - 224. Yates, Abraham, Junr., part of the Document in his autograph. Endorsed: - "Minutes of the Convention which formed the Constitution of the State of New York". Refers to the manner of carrying on elections for Senators & the duties of the Governor & ot, [1777]
  - 225. Yates, Abraham, Junr. A statement of his reasons for voting for the new Constitution, tho he was opposed to it in principle. Also an acknowledgment of the receipt of the above declaration, signed by Ezra L'Hommedieu, Egbert Benson & Alexander Hamilto, 1788 August 8
  - 226. Lansing, Abraham G., to William Barber. Original draft of letter. Referring to the Commissioners of Forfeitures and also to Mr. Robert Barber, "a young gentleman who served some part of his time with Webster and in the Course of a Month I hope he wil, 1788 August 31
  - 227. Metcalfe, George. Acknowledgment of himself an author of an article in the Federal Herald Feb. 18 1788 derogatory to Abraham Yates Junr. & admitting the falseness of the same. Also signed by Thos. Q. Witbeck & Abrm, Reynolds. A. D. S. 1 p. folio, dat, 1789 April 25
  - 228. Burr, Aaron, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Albany. Refers to his illness for several weeks, "I shall consider myself engaged as your Counsel". Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York, 1790 June 13
  - 229. Yates, Robert. Ordering the Sheriff to discharge from custody Thomas as Lewis Spotten & James Spotten of the town of Lansingburg. P. S. 3 p. large folio, 1790 November 5
  - 230. Yates, Abraham, Junr. Also signed by John H. Cook & John De Wandelaer as witnesses. William Angell's warrant of Attorney to Abraham G. Lansing. In autograph of Abm. G. Lansing. D. S. 2 p. folio. AlsoYates, Abraham, Junr., in handwriting of Abm. G. La, 1791 February 25
  - 231. Yates, Robert. discharge of Joseph Tobias, who had been confined in the Albany jail. D. S. 2 p. folio, 1791 March 3
  - 232. Yates, Abraham, Junr., draft of letter- to Aaron Burr. This draft was apparently sent to Robert Yates Esq, for his approval before sending the letter to Burr. Refers to the case against Mr. Ten Broeck, for which Burr was Yates' attorney. 2 p. quarto, 1791 April 24
  - 233. Ten Broeck, Dirck, addressed to the Honbl Abrahan Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany, Referring to some document which he enclosed in the letter, Autograph letter S, 1 p. folio, dated Albany, 1791 June 16
  - 234. Ten Broeck, Dirck, to the Honbl, Atom. Yates Junr. Esqr. An acknowledgment of his error in Judgment as an Inspector of Election in not allowing Abraham Yates' suffrage. A. D. S. 2 p. folio, dated Albany, 1791 June 16
  - 235. Yates, Abraham, Junr., to Dirck Ten Broeck Esq. Relative to the withdrawal of Yates' suit against Ten Broeck. "As the Injury is of a public as well as private nature it is my intention Directly to publish the Certificate", Draft of letter, 1 p. quart, 1791 June 18
  - 236. Ten Broeck. Dirck. An acknowledgment of his error in refusing Yates' vote & agreeing to pay all the costs of the suit brought against him by Yates. A. D. S. 1 p. folio, 1791 July 25
  - 237. Leonard, Enoch An acknowledgment of his error as Inspector of Election in refusing Abm. Yates' vote, & agreeing to pay all the costs of the suit brought against him by Yates. A. D. S. 1 p. folio
  - 238. Yates, Christopher P., addressed to Mr. John Pourteous, Referring to three Judgments against some small estates. Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, 1791 August 14
  - 239. Jay, John (Chief Justice), addressed to The Hon'ble Ab. Yates Esq., Mayor of the City of Albany, Written in the third person, declining Mr. Yates' invitation to take breakfast with him. A. D. 1 p. quarto, 1792
  - 240. Ten Broeck, Abraham (Chairman), Abraham Yates Junr's license for six years to use the books of the Albany Library. Also signed by James Van Ingen, Treasurer. D. S. 1 small square, printed form, 1793 April 10
  - 241. Yates, Abraham, Junr. (Mayor). An Act of the Corporation of the City of Albany "allowing, & permitting a Ferry Stairs to be erected the Wharf opposite to Mark Lane". D. S. 1 p. folio, dated in Common Council, 1793 June 21
  - 242. Political Broadside. Announcement "To the Electors of the State of New York". Requesting the electors to support Jay and Van Rensselaer and containing the names of over 80 prominent citizens of New York. Double-page printed folio, 1795 February 10
  - 243. Ten Broeck, Abraham. Printed Broadside, recommending Gen, Philip Schuyler as a Candidate for the vacant seat of a Member of Senate, Signed by Abm. Ten Broeck as Chairman. 1 p. folio, dated Albany, 1795 April 2
  - 244. Federalism. Printed Broadside, signed "A Republican Elector, Herkimer, April 27, 1807"
    Vigorous attack upon the Federalists and Burr. 1 p. folio.
  - 245. Yates, Joseph C. (Governor), addressed to Christopher Y Lansing. Esquire, Albany. Subscribing for 500 shares of stock of the Commercial Bank. L. S. 1 p. quarto, dated Schenectady, 1825 May 29
- ALPHABETICAL LIST
  - Albany Article from the Albany Argus of Dec. 10, 1899 relative to the pop ulation of Albany in 1697
  - Appleton, Nathaniel, addressed to Mr. Abraham Yates Junr., Commisr. of Loans N. York, Albany. "My case is not in all respects similar to yours, but I am equally excluded from receiving the Continental Taxes. Mr. Morris apologized for this"
    Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Boston Nov 1, 1782.
  - Bancker, Gerard (Treasurer). Receipt given Abraham Yates Junr. for "Interest Facility Certificates" amounting to $72,405. A. D. P. 1 p. folio, dated February 20, 1786
  - Banyar, [DOUBT-], addressed to Abrahan Yates Jun. Esq., high Sheriff of the City and County of Albany. Mentions Mr. Silvester. "I apprehend your office of Sheriff will be looked on as incompatible with that of an Attorney"
    Autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated New York Oct. 4, 1756.
  - Banyar, [DOUBT-], addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., High sheriff of Albany
    Enclosing a copy of the Naturalization Act & mentioning Sir William Johnson' tenants. "If among the others there are any whom you think really unable to pay the Fee on account of their Poverty, I shall leave it with you to forgive the whole or a part as you think proper". A, L. S. 1 p. folio, dated New York, July 16, 1759.
  - Banyar, [DOUBT-], to the Hon. Robert R. Livingston & George Duncan Ludlow, Esquires
    "Some Time after the last River Circuit I was Informed that the Mayor and Magistrates of the City of Albany had, in an Address transmitted to the Lieutenant Governor, asserted in Virtue of the Charter a Right of being appointed Justices of Oyer & Terminer", D. 1 p. folio. copy of original, signed by Richard Morris, dated New York, June 5, 1771.
  - Barber, William, to Abraham Yates Esquire, Bespeaking his assistance in procuring an appointment as a member of the Board of Commissioner
    Autograph letter signed 2 p. quarto, dated Poughkeepsie, Feb. 1, 1787.
  - Benson, Robert (Secretary). Resolves of Congress, signed by him, to give Money on Loan to the Counties mentioned
    Autograph document signed, 2 p. folio, dated In Provincial Congress, New York, March 13, 1776.
  - Bleecker Henry, to John N. Bleecker & Rutger Bleecker, Committee. Also signed by Jacob Bleecker, Jacob Cuyler, Barent Roseboom & others. Stating two questions on which it is requested "that the Inhabitants of this ward Signify their assent or Dissent"
    Document signed, 1 p, folio, dated Albany, March 21, 1775.
  - Brewster, Samuel, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esquire, Albany. Also signed by Jno, Morin Scott, Pierre Van Cortlandt, Paul Spooner & others. "As the only members of the Committee of Safety now present we forward this to you & pray you to make the bes
    Letter signed, 1 p. folio, dated New York, Jan. 2, 1776.
  - Burr, Aaron, addressed to Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr., Albany. Refers to his illness for several weeks. "I shall consider myself engaged as your Counsel"
    Autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto, dated New York, June 13, 1790.
  - Clinton, George (Gov.), copy of his letter to Congress. Long letter explaining the inability of New York State to comply with the requisitions of Congress
    16 p. folio, dated Albany, Feb. 5. 1781.
  - Clinton, George (Gov.), copy of its letter to his Excellency, John Hanson Esq., President of Congress
    Also, Copy of Resolutions of the Senate & Assembly of the State of New York of the 21st November 1781. "They entertain very slender Hopes of their Ability in the present exhausted Condition of the State to comply with any of the Requisitions of Congress". In all 7 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie, Nov, 24. 1781.
  - Clinton, George (Gov.), to the Honble Abraham Yates Junr. Esqr. "The Convention are assembling and in a few Minutes I must take the Chair. The Antis are firm & I hope and believe will remain so to the End"
    Autograph letter, L. 1 p. folio, dated Poughkeepsie, June 28, 1788.
  - Cobhar, William, addressed to Abram. Yates Esq. at Albany, Stating his account against Lewis Deluxe & putting same in Yates hands for collection. autograph letter signed 2 p. folio, dated New York, February 11, 1760
  - Cobham, William, addressed to Abraham Yates Esq. at Albany. "Mr. Hugh Gain has sent all his Accts. to Mr. McComb at Albany", autograph letter signed 1 p. quarto dated New York, March 11, 1760
  - Congress, Committee of. Copies of letters sent to His Excellency George Clinton, Gov, of the State of New York. Also several copies of letters of Gen. Washington, "We again entreat you in the most earnest, in the most urgent Manner, to use every Exertion, May 25, 1780-June 23, 1780
  - Correspondence, Committee of. Drafts of a letter. part of it in the autograph of Abraham Yates Junr., and also resolution passed at a meeting of the Committee of Correspondence of the City & County of Albany, Refers principally to the needs of the Inhabit, December 10, 1774
  - Corry, William, addressed to Mr. Joseph Howard, Merct, In Montreal. Enclosing a bond of Hans Legars due to Alexander McKay. "The news at present is the peace by which Canada is seded to the English". autograph letter signed 1 p. folio, dated Albany, March 11, 1763